Petr Devaikin

Phone: +49 162 4394271 Email: p.devaikin@gmail.com
Location: Berlin, Germany Website: http://petrdevaikin.com

Profile

I am a UX/Interaction designer and creative technologist with an entrepreneurial mindset. My passion for a user-centred approach, combined with a strong technical background, helps me to design seamless human-machine interaction and create concepts which meet user needs. In addition to making technology human-oriented, I like to explore the intersection of tech, art and science.

Skills and Tools

UX Research Qualitative and quantitative studies, evaluation of interactive systems

UX Design User journeys, personas, wireframing, prototyping

Sketch, Adobe CC, InVision, Flinto

Creative Development Processing, openFrameworks, Unity3D, Arduino

Web Development HTML5, CSS3, Stylus, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery

Python/Flask, Node.js, Ruby/Rails

Data Visualization D3.js

Education

2015 – 2018	Master Degree in Human C	Computer Interaction and Design
-------------	--------------------------	---------------------------------

with Minor in Innovation and Entrepreneurship

EIT Digital Master School. Paris-Saclay (Paris-Sud), France. TU Berlin, Germany

2010 – 2012 Master Degree in Informatics and Computer Engineering

Bauman Moscow State Technical University, Russia

2006 – 2010 Bachelor Degree in Informatics and Computer Engineering

Bauman Moscow State Technical University, Russia

Work Experience

Jan. 2019 - May 2019

Expert UX Designer and Concept Developer at MBition (Berlin, Germany)

http://mbition.io 5 months

Oct. 2017 - Dec. 2018

Senior UX Designer and Concept Developer at MBition (Berlin, Germany)

1.5 years http://mbition.io

> Creating concepts for the new generation of Mercedes-Benz in-car infotainment system and connected services, including mobile and web

applications.

Planning and conducting qualitative and quantitative user studies.

Supporting building UX-related processes in the company.

June 2016 — Dec. 2016 Interaction Design Intern at Artificial Rome (Berlin, Germany)

http://www.artificialrome.com 7 months

Design and development of interactive web, mobile and VR projects

May 2015 – May 2016

UX/UI Designer and Front-end Developer at Lobster IT (London, UK)

http://lobster.media 1 year

Design and front-end development for a start-up, which builds a

user-generated content market

Dec. 2011 - July 2015

Senior Developer at CitySoft (Moscow, Russia)

3.5 years

http://citysoftgroup.ru

Creating prototypes and development of complex web, mobile and

eHealth systems

May 2010 - Sep. 2011

Software Developer at Banks Soft Systems (Moscow, Russia)

http://bssys.com 1.5 years

Front-end development of online banking systems

Extra Information

Languages Russian – native,

> English – fluent, German — beginner, French – beginner

Hobbies Interactive art,

CrossFit